Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is a weather lady! Pager logic will clear the heart!
!حلقة اليوم عن مذيعة الطقس
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ دماغه لبالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Towels, towels!
!مناشف! مناشف
A little more and we'd be super-sopping wet...
كدنا نتبلّل حتّى تغرق ثيابنا
The weather lady was right! Thunderstorms this afternoon!
،عواصف رعديّة ظهيرة اليوم !أي أنّ مذيعة الطقس أصابت
Huh? Where's Mr. Mori?
ماذا؟ أين العمّ موري؟
He's on a work trip.
خرج في رحلة عمل
Huh? There's a message on here.
ماذا؟ توجد رسالة على الآلة
Hey, now. Don't go touching it.
أنتم، لا تلمسوها
You have one message.
لديك رسالة واحدة
Geez.
يا إلهي
Hello, this is Asano Aki from Nichiuri TV.
مرحباً، أنا أسانو آكي من تلفاز نيتشيوري
I'm calling because I need to speak with you about something urgent.
أتّصل لأنّي بحاجة للكلام معك في موضوعٍ عاجل
You appear to be out, so I'll call again later.
لا يبدو أنّك موجود، لذا سأعاود الاتّصال لاحقاً
Who's Asano Aki?
من أسانو آكي هذه؟
The weather lady! You know, she does the weather on Nichiuri TV!
مذيعة الطقس! تلك التي تقدّم نشرة !الطقس في تلفاز نيتشيوري
Yeah! She's on "News City" too!
!صحيح! تظهر في "مدينة الأخبار" أيضاً
She's super cool! I'm a big fan of hers!
!إنّها رائعةٌ جدّاً! وأنا معجبة كبيرة لها
But what could she urgently need to talk to him about?
لكن ما هو الموضوع العاجل الذي تريد الكلام فيه؟
Alright! Let's talk with her instead, as the Junior Detective League!
حسناً، لنذهب نحن فرقة فتيان التحرّي !للكلام معها بالمقابل
Yeah!
!أجل
Hey, now...
...أنتم
Nichiuri TV
تلفاز نيتشيوري
Asano Aki (27) Weather lady and newscaster
(أسانو آكي (27 مذيعة طقس وأنباء
So you came all the way here in Mori-san's place?
أتيتم مكان موري-سان إلى هنا؟
Yes! If you need help, leave it to us, the Junior Detective League!
أجل، يمكنكِ الاعتماد علينا إذا !كان لديكِ حاجة
Oh, are you greeting children today?
ماذا؟ تقومين باستضافة أطفالٍ اليوم؟
Tsukumo-san...
...تسوكومو-سان
Having to deal with kids just to gain popularity...
...التعامل مع الأطفال لمجرّد كسب الشعبيّة
Tsukumo Kazumi (31) Newscaster
(تسوكومو كازومي (31 مذيعة أخبار
Big-name newscasters sure have it tough!
المذيعات لامعات الاسم يعانين حقّاً
What's with that fingernail?
ما خطب أظفرها هذا؟
That's not what I'm doing.
لم يكن ذلك ما أنويه
Behave yourselves, kiddies. Don't get in the way of her work.
يا صغار، عليكم التصرّف بتهذيب كيلا تعيقوها في عملها
What an unpleasant person!
إنّها امرأة بغيضة
Isn't she the person who did the news before you did?
أليست المذيعة التي كانت تقدّم الأخبار قبلك؟
That's right. We switched places about half a year ago.
صحيح، تبادلنا أماكننا قبل نصف عام تقريباً
Was she what you wanted to talk to Mr. Mori about?
أكانت هي الموضوع الذي أردتِ الكلام مع العمّ موري فيه؟
No... A-Actually, uhh...
...كلا، فـ-في الواقع
I was wondering if Detective Mori-san would be on News City!
كنتُ أتساءل إذا ما كان بإمكان المتحرّي "موري-سان الظهور في "مدينة الأخبار
Aww, what a downer.
هذا فقط؟ يا للملل
What a relief it wasn't a case...
...من الحسن أنّها لم تكن قضيّة
What's that sound?
ما هذا الصوت؟
What is that?
ما هو؟
It's a pager.
جهاز مناداة
Ran-neechan told me to take it because I always suddenly disappear.
أخبرتني ران-نيتشان بأخذه معي لأنّي أختفي فجأةً دوماً
Oh! You're so lucky!
!يا لحظّك
You had a cell phone, Mitsuhiko!
!كان لديك هاتف خلويّ يا ميتسوهيكو
It was only a receiver!
كان لاقطاً فحسب
But it broke, right?
وتحطّم، صحيح؟
Yes, for the sake of justice...
...أجل، لأجل العدالة
Oh? Really?
حقّاً؟
Oh, this is the detective agency's number, so it must be Ran-neechan!
هذا رقم وكالة التحرّي، فلا بدّ أنّها ران-نيتشان
Oh, I know! Could you give me your pager's number?
صحيح، أيمكنك إعطائي رقم جهاز مناداتك يا فتى؟
I can contact you when I need the Junior Detective League's help!
سأتّصل بكم متى أردت طلب مساعدة فرقة فتيان التحرّي
Awesome! Hey, Conan!
!هذا مذهل! كونان
Sure! It's written right here!
أجل، إنّه مكتوبٌ هنا
Thanks!
شكراً لك
Let's see... Now to save "Junior Detective League" to my phone...
"حسناً... سأحفظ "فرقة فتيان التحرّي ...في ذاكرة الهاتف
There we go! All done!
انتهيت
My friends and I often used numbers to write messages for fun!
كنتُ ألهو مع أصدقائي بكتابة رسائل عبر الأرقام كثيراً
Messages?
رسائل؟
Even if it can only display numbers,
،حتّى لو كان يعرض الأرقام فقط
you can use numbers that look and sound like letters to write things!
يمكنكم استعمال أرقام تشابه مظهر أو نطق الحروف لكتابة كلمات كثيرة
For example, "428" could be read "Shibuya"!
على سبيل المثال، يمكن أن تُقرأ "428" بأنّها شيبويا
4, 2, 8... Shi-bu-ya...
...أربعة، اثنان، ثمانية
Shibuya! (a city in Tokyo) Neat!
!شيبويا! فهمنا
Say, since you're here, how about a tour of the News City studio?
وجدتُها، ما رأيكم بأخذ جولة في استوديو مدينة الأخبار" بما أنّكم هنا؟"
Yes!
!رائع
Oh, just a minute.
أمهلوني قليلاً
Hello, this is Asano.
أجل، أنا أسانو
Yes. Yes. I will. Yes. Okay. I'll be right there.
أجل، أجل، سأفعل ذلك
I'm sorry. I have work to do, so I can't go.
آسفة، لديّ عملٌ الآن فعليّ الذهاب
I-I'm sorry!
!آ-آسفة
Oh, Kobayashi-san!
!كوباياشي-سان
Yes? What can I do?
أجل؟ ما الأمر؟
I'm sorry to ask, but could you show them to Studio A?
أعتذر على الطلب، لكن هلّا اصطحبت هؤلاء الأطفال إلى الاستوديو أ؟
Some work just came up, so...
...طرأ لي عملٌ، لذا
Sure, it's no problem!
أجل، لا مشكلة
Oh, and could you get them some passes?
وهلّا أعطيتهم تصاريحاً أيضاً؟
Sure.
أجل
Well, shall we go?
حسناً، هل نذهب؟
Hurray!
!رائع
I'm hungry...
...أشعر بالجوع
How long is she going to make us wait?
لمتى ستجعلنا ننتظر؟
Sorry to suddenly ask you to stand in like this!
أعتذر على طلبك شغل مكانها فجأةً
That's fine, but what's this about Aki-san being threatened?
لا أمانع، لكن هل تعرّضت آكي-سان للتهديد حقّاً؟
Threatened?!
!تهديد؟
Who are these kids?! They're distracting! Get rid of them!
!ما خطب هؤلاء الأطفال؟ إنّهم يشتّتون انتباهي، أخرجوهم
U-Understood!
!حـ-حسناً
Running off because of a threat?! Aki-san is a failure as a journalist!
تهرب لمجرّد تلقّيها تهديداً؟ آكي-سان !ليست مؤهلة كمذيعة
We're beginning rehearsal!
!سنبدأ التجربة
Sorry, Kazumi-san hates children.
آسف، كازومي-سان تمقت الأطفال
Say, she said Aki-san was threatened.
أخبرني، ألم تقل أنّ آكي-سان تتعرّض للتهديد؟
Yeah.
بلى
We came to see Aki-san in Detective Mori's place!
أتينا للقاء آكي-سان هنا مكان المتحرّي موري
Oh, the famous detective?!
ذاك المتحرّي الشهير؟
I see. Well, just between us,
...فهمت، حسناً
Aki-san's been getting harassing letters and phone calls
كانت آكي-سان تتلقّى رسائل ومكالمات مضايقات
ever since she started a story about a certain politician's corruption.
مذ بدأت قصّةً عن فساد أحد السياسيّين
She got a letter this morning threatening to kill her
تلقّت رسالة تهديد بقتلها
if she appeared on today's News City.
إذا ظهرت في حلقة "مدينة الأخبار" اليوم
Was this threat what she really wanted to discuss?
أكان هذا التهديد هو الموضوع الذي أرادت الكلام فيه حقّاً؟
You can see the News City broadcast on that TV.
"يمكنكم متابعة بثّ "مدينة الأخبار على هذا التلفاز
Well, I have work to do, so I'll see you later.
.حسناً، لديّ عملٌ الآن أراكم لاحقاً
Hey, do you think the phone call Aki-san got earlier
اسمعوا، أتظنّ الاتّصال الذي ورد آكي-سان قبل قليل
was a threatening phone call?!
كان مكالمة تهديد؟
Yes, and then that scared her...
...صحيح، وأخافها ذلك
No! Aki-san isn't a weakling like that!
!كلا! ليست آكي-سان ضعيفةً هكذا
You agree with me, right, Conan-kun?!
أليس كذلك؟ توافقني يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah...
أجل
When she was on the phone then, she didn't seem afraid at all.
،عندما كانت تتكلّم بالهاتف آنذاك لم يبد أنّها خائفة البتّة
In fact, she sounded happy, as if she had gotten a special scoop.
بل بدت مسرورةً كما لو تلقّت سبقاً خاصّاً
That call was probably not a threat.
لم يكن ذاك الاتّصال تهديداً على الأرجح
No, wait! If that call had been a trap to lure her somewhere--!
لحظة، انتظر
Is it Ran-oneechan again?
أهي ران-نيتشان مُجدداً؟
No.
كلا
It's probably Aki-san. Only she and Ran-neechan know this number.
إنّها آكي-سان غالباً، فهي وران-نيتشان وحدهما من تعرفان رقم جهاز مناداتي
Oh! Okay!
هكذا إذاً، فهمت
Hello, this is Asano. I'm not home right now, so please leave your--
،مرحباً، أنا أسانو. لستُ في المنزل الآن ...لذا إن كان لديك
Huh? Why'd you hang up?
ماذا؟ لمَ أغلقته؟
Was it not Aki-san?
لم تكن آكي-سان؟
It was her home. But it was her answering machine.
كان منزلها، لكن أجابت عليّ آلة الرد
That's odd! Why would she have you call her home if she isn't there?
هذا غريب، لمَ قد تطلب منك الاتّصال بمنزلها إذا لم تكن فيه؟
110?
واحد واحد صفر؟
The police phone number.
رقم الطوارئ
The police?!
الطوارئ؟ أليست الشرطة؟
Why would the police call us?!
لمَ قد تتّصل بنا الشرطة؟
No! It's Aki-san!
!كلا! إنّها آكي-سان
A bad guy must've caught her! So she wants us to call the police!
لا بدّ أنّ شريراً أمسك بها! لذا تريد منّا إخبار الشرطة، أليس كذلك؟
Then couldn't she just call them herself?
بإمكانها فعل ذلك بنفسها إذاً
What if she's unable to talk?
ماذا لو كانت عاجزةً عن الكلام؟
Oh no!
!كلا
It's an abduction...
...إنّه اختطاف
9109.
تسعة واحد صفر تسعة
That's the city code of her phone number!
هذا رمز مدينة رقم هاتفها، أليس كذلك؟
The police won't listen to us with only this.
لن تصغي الشرطة لنا بمجرّد هذه الرسالة
If the police can't help, then the Junior Detective League will!
إذا لم تساعدنا الشرطة، فعلينا نحن !فرقة فتيان التحرّي التصرّف
Yeah, but this isn't enough to know where she is.
أجل، لكن لا يمكننا معرفة أين هي من هذه الرسالة فقط
Oh...
صحيح
Yeah...
...أجل
And now for today's sports.
وإلى أنباء اليوم الرياضيّة
The J-League game at the National Stadium between the Tokyo--
في مباراة الدوريّ الأوّل التي جرت في الملعب ..."الوطنيّ بين "طوكيو سبيرتس" و"بيغ أوساكا
I like Aki-san a lot better...
آكي-سان أفضل منها بالفعل
2003.
اثنان صفر صفر ثلاثة
I got it! It's read "Niousama"! [temple guardian]
!"وجدتُها! تُقرأ هذه "ني أوساما
So she's where there are temple guardian statues!
لذا لا بدّ أنّها موجودة في مكان !به حرّاس معبد
Come on. Can't you deduce a little better than that?
ألا تستطيع التفكير باستنتاج معقول أكثر؟
The messages after 7:20 make no sense at all.
لا نستطيع فهم معنى الرسائل بعد السابعة والثلث البتّة
Lastly, we've just received this news.
ختاماً، وصلتنا هذه الأنباء للتوّ
The Special Investig. Unit of the Tokyo Public Prosecutor's Office
ستقوم فرقة التحقيق الخاصّة لمكتب المدّعي العام لشرطة طوكيو
is to question the politicians Mr. Maruya and Mr. Okubo tomorrow
باستجواب السياسيّين، السيّد مارويا والسيّد أوكوبو
about their possible acceptance of large bribes
غداً بشأن احتمال قبولهما لرشاوٍ كبيرة
in relation to the corruption case involving Bay Development.
مرتبطة بقضيّة الفساد في مشروع تطوير الخليج
I've figured out what Aki-san's messages mean!
!فهمتُ معنى رسالة آكي-سان
For reals, Mitsuhiko?!
!حقّاً يا ميتسوهيكو؟
These are indicating the names of the politicians who took bribes!
تُظهر هذه أرقام السياسيّين !اللذين تلقّوا رشاوياً
0 is "maru". Maruya's initial, basically!
!الصفر هو "مارو"، أي حرف "مارويا" الأوّل
00 is "oo." Okubo's initial!
!والصفران هما "أو"، أي حرف "أوكوبو" الأوّل
And the 96 of 096 is "kuro"!
،"و96 في 096 هي "كورو
So Aki-san is trying to say it's Maruya who's guilty of corruption!
أي كانت آكي-سان تحاول إيصال أنّ !مارويا هو المذنب بالفساد
Then what do 2003 and 5656 mean?
ما معنى 2003 و5656 إذاً؟
They're bank account numbers used for the bribes, of course!
...إنّهما بالطبع
Alright! Aki-san must be captured at Maruya's home then!
حسناً! لا بدّ أنّ آكي-سان محتجزة !في منزل مارويا إذاً
Let's hurry and save her!
!لنذهب لإنقاذها بسرعة
I heard he lives in West Teitan, one subway stop from here!
سمعتُ أنّ منزول مارويا موجود في حيّ تيتان الغربيّ على بعد محطّة أنفاق واحدة من هنا
Let's go, Conan-kun!
!هيّا بنا يا كونان-كن
Okay.
أجل
Now there's thunder! Let's run, guys!
الرعد يدوي، لنركض يا رفاق
Maruya
مارويا
Hey, Conan! Hurry up! Conan!
!كونان! تعال بسرعة! كونان
Keep watch for anyone coming!
راقب قدوم أيّ أحد
Mitsuhiko! Hurry up here!
!ميتسوهيكو! اصعد بسرعة
Right!
!حسناً
Hey, you! What are you doing?!
!أنتم! ما الذي تفعلونه؟
Come down here!
!انزل من عندك
I'm sorry!
!آسف
Can't believe you guys ran off without me.
كيف لكم أن تهربوا وتتركوني وراءكم؟
Next time, we'll have to do something about the guard and the dogs.
علينا فعل شيءٍ حيال الكلاب والحارس عند تسلّلنا المرّة القادمة
You saw them first!
!أنت أوّل من رآهم
Stop it!
!توقّف
Aki-san?!
!آكي-سان؟
It's Ran-neechan.
إنّها ران-نيتشان
Oh...
ماذا؟
I'll go call her!
سأذهب للاتّصال بها
Hello? Ran-neechan?
مرحباً؟ ران-نيتشان؟
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Where are you at this time of night?!
!أين أنت في هذا الوقت المتأخّر؟
I paged you and paged you, but you ignored me!
!اتّصلت بجهاز مناداتك في المساء، لكنّك تجاهلتني
S-Sorry! I'll be home soon!
!آ-آسف! سأرجع قريباً
You better come home quick!
!ارجع بسرعة
Huh? There's thunder where you are?
ماذا؟ لديكم رعد هناك؟
Yea, it's really rainy and thundery.
أجل، إنّه قويّ، وكذلك هطول المطر
It's nice weather here. The moon is really pretty!
الطقس صحوٌ هنا، والقمر بغاية الجمال
It's pouring here, so I don't think I'll be home for a while.
المطر يهطل بغزارة، فلا أظنّني سأقدر على العودة لفترة
Where are you right now, Conan-kun?
أين أنت الآن يا كونان-كن؟
Should I bring an umbrella and come get you?
هل أجلب مظلّة وآتي لاصطحابك؟
Moon?
القمر؟
What? Hello? Conan-kun? Hey, are you listening to me?
ماذا؟ مرحباً، كونان-كن؟
Now for tomorrow's weather.
إلى أنباء طقس الغد
A cold front in the northern Kanto region will bring clouds and rain.
ستجلب موجة برد في منطقة كانتو الشماليّة غيوماً ومطراً معها
Southern Kanto will have clear skies. Tomorrow's high temperature...
بينما سيكون الطقس صحواً في منطقة ...كانتو الجنوبيّة، وإلى درجات حرارة الغد العظمى
We're going back to the TV station!
!سنرجع لمحطّة التلفاز
Hurry, everyone!
!بسرعة يا رفاق
Wait up!
!انتظر
You better explain, Conan!
!فـ-فسّر الأمر يا كونان
Here, try reading 2003 on its side.
اسمعوا، جرّبوا قراءة 2003 من الجانب
On its side?
الجانب؟
M-O-O-N.
"إم-أو-أو-إن"
So, what's that mean?
لكن، ما معناها؟
It spells "moon" in English.
تُقرأ "قمر" بالإنجليزيّة
Now, the reason Aki-san sent this "2003" message first
اسمعوا، سبب إرسال آكي-سان لرسالة 2003 في البداية
was because she wanted us to look up at the night sky.
هو لأنّها أرادت منّا النظر إلى السماء
The "2003" was displayed at 7:20 pm.
عُرضت 2003 عند السابعة والثلث ليلاً، صحيح؟
As I recall, the moon was in the southeast then.
وفقما أذكر، فقد كان القمر في الجانب الجنوب شرقيّ وقتها
But it wasn't visible from Maruya's mansion,
لكن لم يكن مرئيّاً من قصر مارويا
because of buildings to the southeast.
بسبب المباني المواجهة في الجنوب الشرقيّ
Which means Aki-san isn't at Maruya's home, right?!
أي أنّ آكي-سان ليست في منزل مارويا؟
Right... she's being held somewhere where she can see the moon.
أجل، إنّها محتجزة في مكانٍ يمكنك رؤية القمر منه
But that isn't enough to tell us where she is.
لكن لا يكفي القمر لإخبارنا أين هي
Exactly.
صحيح
So she used numbers like weather symbols
لذا استعملت الأرقام كرموزٍ للطقس
to indicate weather changes where she is!
كي تشير لتغيّر الطقس في المكان الذي هي فيه
0 is the circle meaning fair weather.
الصفر يعني الدائرة، أي طقس صحو
00 is the double-circle meaning cloudy weather.
والصفران هما دائرتان، أي طقس غائم
096 is a filled circle, meaning rain!
و096 هي دائرة ممتلئة، أي المطر
What about the 5656 at 8:31?
ماذا عن 5656 عند الثامنة وواحد وثلاثين دقيقة إذاً؟
Say the sound effect for thunder out loud.
انطقي تعبير الرعد
"Goro (56) goro (56)"...
"غورو غورو"
I get it! 5656 was referring to thunder!
!فهمت! كانت 5656 تشير للرعد
Yep!
أجل
So she's being held where there was rain and thunder around 8:30!
لذا فهي محتجزة في مكانٍ كان يهطل !فيه المطر ويدوي الرعد عند الثامنة والنصف
Places with thunderstorms at 8:30 pm?
أماكن بعواصف رعديّة عند الثامنة والنصف مساء اليوم؟
Oh, the only one was the area around this TV station
المنطقة الوحيدة هي محيط محطّة التلفاز هذه
Nichiuri TV Meteorology Center
مركز تلفاز نيتشيوري للأرصاد الجويّة
within a 1-kilometer radius!
بما يقارب نصف قطر كيلومتر واحد
It was a passing shower!
كانت أمطاراً عابرة
Thanks!
!شكراً
It's just as you thought! Aki-san is somewhere in this area!
كما ظننتَ يا كونان-كن، آكي-سان موجودةٌ بالقرب من هنا
Yeah.
أجل
0109... What is it?
صفر واحد صفر 9، ما هذا؟
Wouldn't 01 be the symbol for "clear weather"?!
أليس 01 رمز الطقس الصحو؟
No, it's still cloudy here. It must mean something different.
،كلا، لا تزال المنطقة هنا غائمة فلا بدّ أنّ مقصدها آخر
I bet 0109 means, "I want to eat a huge eel box lunch!"
...لا بدّ أنّ 0109 تعني
After all, she's probably hungry!
!فهي جائعة على الأرجح
I think you mean you.
ذلك أنت فحسب
I'm hungry...
...أشعر بالجوع
What's your problem?! It's not that funny!
!ما مشكلتك؟! الأمر ليس مضحكاً لهذا الحدّ
Sorry, sorry! That's not it! Nice work, Genta!
!آسف، آسف! ليس الأمر هكذا !أحسنتَ يا غينتا
Thanks to you, I know where Aki-san is!
!بفضلك، عرفت مكان آكي-سان
The large prop room?
غرفة المعدّات الكبيرة؟
Yeah! That's where we got separated from her!
أجل، انفصلنا عنها هناك
As I recall, it's the northernmost room on the first floor...
أظنّها كانت الغرفة في أقصى الشمال ...في الطابق الأوّل
Thanks!
!شكراً لك
H-Hey!
!مـ-مهلك
Aki-san's in the large prop room!
!آكي-سان في غرفة المعدّات الكبيرة
Like Genta said, you read the 0, 10, and 9 of that 0109 separately!
رمز 0109 يٌقرأ بـ صفر، 10، و9 على حدة كما قلتَ يا غينتا
0, 10, 9? O... to... ku? Odogu! (large prop)
صفر، 10، 9... "أو-تو-كو"؟
There are lots of rooms in TV stations that people rarely enter!
توجد غرف كثيرة في محطّات التلفاز نادراً ما يدخلها الناس
If the kidnapper works here, they could use one!
،إذا كان المختطف يعمل هنا !فمن المحتمل أنّه يستعمل إحداها
Does that mean you know who it is?!
أتقصد أنّك عرفت هويّته؟
Yeah, because Aki-san told us who!
أخبرتني آكي-سان بذلك بجهاز المناداة
End of the line!
!هذه هي النهاية
It's no use running.
لا جدوى من الهرب
We know everything.
نعرف كلّ شيء
Give yourself up.
سلّم نفسك
You called Aki-san here, knocked her out with drugs or something,
،استدعيت آكي-سان إلى هنا بالهاتف وأفقدتها وعيها بمنومٍ وما شابه
and locked her in that back room
واحتجزتها في تلك الغرفة الخلفيّة
to make others think she had run away, out of fear of that threat.
كي يعتقد الجميع أنّها هربت ذعراً بعد تلقّيها للتهديد
Yes, you tried to ruin her credibility and have her kicked off News City!
أجل، حاولت تشويه مصداقيّة آكي-سان "وطردها من "مدينة الأخبار
Aki-san used her cell phone to send us messages about her location
استعملت آكي-سان هاتفها الخلويّ لإرسال رسائل تشير لموقعها إلى جهازا مناداتي
by referencing weather changes she could see outside the window!
عبر تحديد التغيّرات في الطقس التي !يمكنها مشاهدتها عبر النافذة
Except, there was one message she sent that I didn't understand.
لكن كانت هنالك رسالة واحدة لها لم أفهمها
9109.
تسعة واحد صفر تسعة
This number came in after a message to call the police.
تبع هذا الرقم رسالة طلبها الاتّصال بالشرطة
But, if it didn't indicate her location...
...لكن إذا لم يكن يشير لموقعها
...it indicated her kidnapper's name!
!فهو يحدّد اسم المختطف
Oh, no, you don't!
!لن تهرب
Take this!
!خذ
We're the Junior Detective League! There's no getting away from us!
يستحيل أن تهرب من قبضة !فرقة فتيان التحرّي
That's right!
!أجل، صحيح
Aki-san! Hang on! Aki-san!
!آكي-سان! تماسكي! آكي-سان
9109 is separated as 9-10-9. Changed to kanji and read aloud...
...افصل 9109 إلى 9-10-9، ثمّ اقلبها للكانجي واقرأها
... "tsu ku mo."
"تسو كو مو"
That would be you, Tsukumo Kazumi-san!
!أي أنت يا تسوكومو كازومي-سان
Get off me!
!انهضوا عنّي
I just couldn't stand it...
لم أستطع الاحتمال
News City was my idea! It was my show from the start!
!كانت "مدينة الأخبار" فكرتي أنا !كانت برنامجي الذي عملت عليه منذ البداية
But then they replaced me with someone younger, someone cuter!
لكنّهم استبدلوني فورما انضمّت فتاة !أصغر وأكثر ظرافة
This is serious business! This is...
!لا تعبثوا معي
Then earn the spot back with actual skill.
فلترجعي باستعمال قدراتك إذاً
However you rationalize it, a crime can't be justified.
،مهما أوجدتِ للجريمة من أعذار فلا يمكن تبريرها
That concludes this afternoon's weather forecast!
!وهذه نهاية أنباء الطقس لظهيرة اليوم
And cut!
!اقطع
Good work!
!عملٌ موفق
Sorry for the wait!
شكراً لانتظاركم
Thank you all so much for yesterday!
أنا ممتنةٌ لكم على ما فعلتموه بالأمس يا صغار
But only the Junior Detective League could've realized
،لكن إدراككم لكون رسائلي شفرات للطقس
that my messages were weather codes!
تظهر أنّ فرقة فتيان التحرّي مميّزة بالفعل
But how did you know it was Kazumi-san?
كيف عرفتِ بدورك أنّ الفاعلة هي كازومي-سان؟
When she tried to put me to sleep, I caught a glimpse of her nails.
لمحت أظفرها عندما كانت تحاول تنويمي
Oh! The nail art!
!فهمت! تخطيط الأظفر
Yep! The design reminded me of a weather map, so I remembered it.
،أجل، ذكّرني التصميم بخريطة للطقس فعلق الأمر بذهني
That means you're snow pellets, Genta-kun!
!هذا يعني أنّك حبيبات ثلج يا غينتا-كن
Snow pellets?
حبيبات ثلج؟
See?!
!انظر
Snow Pellets
حبيبات ثلج
Ah! That image fits you perfectly!
!فهمت! الصورة تطابقك تماماً
Hey, you!
!أنتما
Hey, Genta. You're not just snow pellets.
غينتا، لستَ حبيبات ثلجٍ فحسب
Hail
بَرَد
Hail!
!بَرَد
Looks pretty tense.
تبدو بغاية التوتّر، من يكون طويل الشعر ذاك؟
What's this doing here?
لمَ قد يوجد شيء كهذا؟
Wait a minute.
!انتظر
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Spotlight.
بقعة تسليط ضوء
Next episode is an original story.
!قصّة الحلقة القادمة أصليّة
Wow!
!مذهل
What does that mean?
ما المقصود بالأصليّة؟
What?
ماذا؟